RUILONG LI

http://www.liruilong.cn/ruilongl@usc.edu, (+1)213-245-6790
12015 Waterfront Drive, Playa Vista, CA 90094-2536

I am a second year PhD student at the University of Southern California and Research Assistant at the USC Institute for Creative Technologies, advised by Prof. Hao Li. My current research interests widely spread in Computer Vision & Graphics & Machine Learning, especially in representation learning of human body, face and motion.

EDUCATION

Ph.D - University of Southern California, Los Angeles, USA

Sept. 2019 - Present

Major: Computer Science

Research Group: Vision & Graphics Lab, USC Institute for Creative Technologies

Advisor: Prof. Hao Li

Research Topics: 3D human synthesis and digitization.

M.Eng. - Tsinghua University, Beijing, China

Sept. 2016 - July 2019

Major: Computer Science and Technology

Research Group: Graphics & Geometry Computing Group Co-Advisor: Prof. Shi-Min Hu and Prof. Song-Hai Zhang

Research Topics: Image detection, segmentation; Human pose estimation; Image generation.

B.S. - Tsinghua University, Beijing, China

Sept. 2012 - July 2016

Major: Mathematics and Physics

PULICATIONS

Ruilong Li*, Shan Yang*, David Ross and Angjoo Kanazawa. Learn to Dance with AIST++: Music Conditioned 3D Dance Generation. In Submission. (* equal contribution)

Ruilong Li, Kyle Olszewski, Yuliang Xiu, Shunsuke Saito, Zeng Huang and Hao Li. Volumetric Human Teleportation. Siggraph Real-time Live 2020. [Link] Best Show Award

Ruilong Li*, Yuliang Xiu*, Shunsuke Saito, Zeng Huang, Kyle Olszewski and Hao Li. *Monocular Real-Time Volumetric Performance Capture.* ECCV 2020. [Link] (* equal contribution)

Ruilong Li*, Karl Bladin*, Yajie Zhao*, Chinmay Chinara, Owen Ingraham, Pengda Xiang, Xinglei Ren, Pratusha Prasad, Bipin Kishore, Jun Xing and Hao Li. *Learning Formation of Physically-Based Face Attributes*. CVPR 2020. [Link] (* equal contribution)

Miao Wang, Guo-Ye Yang, **Ruilong Li**, Run-Ze Liang, Song-Hai Zhang, Peter Hall and Shi-Min Hu. *Example-Guided Image Synthesis using Adversarial Networks with Genre Consistency*. **CVPR 2019**. [Link]

Song-Hai Zhang, Ruilong Li †, Xin Dong, Paul L. Rosin, Zixi Cai, Xi Han, Dingcheng Yang, Haozhi Huang and Shi-Min Hu. *Pose2Seg: Detection Free Human Instance Segmentation*. **CVPR 2019**. († first student author) [Link]

Xian Wu, Ruilong Li, Fang-Lue Zhang, Jian-Cheng Liu, Jue Wang, Ariel Shamir and Shi-Min Hu.

Deep Portrait Image Completion and Extrapolation. IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP) 2019. [Link]

Fang-Lue Zhang, Xian Wu, **RuiLong Li**, Zhao-Heng Zheng, Jue Wang and Shi-Min Hu. *Detecting and Removing Visual Distractors for Video Aesthetic Enhancement*. **IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (TMM) 2018**. [Link]

POSITIONS

Google Research, Mountain View, CA, USA

May 2020 - Present

Research Intern

- · Group: Perception Team
- · Research topic: Conditional music 3D human motion generation.
- · Mentor: Shan Yang and Angjoo Kanazawa

USC Institute for Creative Technologies

Aug 2019 - Present

Research Assistant

- · Group: Vision & Graphics Lab
- · Research topic: 3D human synthesis and digitization.
- · Mentor: Hao Li

Bytedance AI Lab, Beijing, China

June 2017 - Aug. 2017

Research Intern

- · Research topic: Real-time CNN on mobile device for hair matting and re-color.
- · Algorithm integrated into FaceU APP, becoming the top selfie filter most commonly used in the quarter.

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Reviewer: CVPR20, CVPR21, ACCV20, WACV21, Eurographics21.

AWARDS & HONORS

ACM SIGGRAPH Real-time Live! 2020 "Best In Show" Award, ACM SIGGRAPH.	2020
6th/182, AIChallenger Global Competition, Human Pose Estimation Track.	2017
Best Demo Award, China Multimedia Conference (ChinaMM)	2017
Kwang-Hua Scholarship, Tsinghua University	2014
Top 200 (0.04%), Chinese Physics Olympiad (CPhO)	2012

TEACHING ASSITANT

C++ Programming Design, Tsinghua University.

Spring 2017

SKILLS & TESTS

Skilled Knowledge: Python, Matlab

Basic Knowledge: JavaScript, Html, CSS, Linux

Techniques: OpenGL, OpenCV, Pytorch, Caffe, Tensorflow